Guide to the Alfred Schütz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Alfred Schutz papers
1868-2005
GEN MSS 129
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
25.38
(48 boxes)
The Alfred Schutz papers consist of manuscripts, letters, teaching notes and printed materials relating to the work of Schutz, mainly that done at the New School for Social Research. Among the Writings are drafts of many of Schutz's major works, including "Die Strukturen der Lebenswelt" and many essays discussing the works of philosophers such as Edmund Husserl, Max Weber and George Santayana, among others. Series II, Teaching and Research Materials, consists of lecture and course materials prepared for classes which Schutz taught, and reading notes on various topics. Series III, Subject Files and Correspondence, contains letters, writings by others, and materials from organizations. Among the correspondents are Raymond Aron, Kurt Goldstein, Karl Lowith, Fritz Machlup, Jacques Maritain, Maurice Merleau-Ponty, Karl Popper, Meyer Schapiro, Leo Strauss, Eric Voegelin, Jean Wahl, and Kurt Wolff.
Schutz, Alfred, 1899-1959
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated to the Beinecke Library by Mrs. Alfred Schütz in 1978 and 1986, with later additions from Alfred Schütz's children, Mrs. Evelyn Lang and Mr. George F. Schutz, in 1990 and 2003.
April 2013 Acquisition: gift of Evelyn S. Lang, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Papers in box 36 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
ALFRED SCHÜTZ (1899-1959)
Alfred Schütz was born in Vienna on April 13, 1899. His early education at the Esterhazy Gymnasium was concluded with a comprehensive emergency examination in order for him to enter the Austrian army. Upon his return to Vienna in late 1918, he was faced with the choice of creating a civilian career in the devastated post World-War Austrian economy. He chose to study law as well as international trade, preparing himself for employment in the field of banking. He began working with various public and private banking concerns in the late 1920s In 1926, he married Ilse Heim.
While he was pursuing a career in the field of finance, Schütz never ceased his studies. He focused on the sociological school of thinking that was based in Vienna, studying with and becoming close colleagues with Ludwig von Mises. By the late 1920s, Schütz had written a manuscript born out of his study of Bergson and Weber, "Lebensformen and Sinnstruktur." After encountering the published works of Edmund Husserl, Schütz wrote and published Der sinnhafte Aufbau der sozialen Welt in 1932. This was followed by a meeting with Husserl, himself, firmly positing Schütz as a proponent of the developing thesis of phenomenology.
From 1933 to 1938, Alfred Schütz continued to expand his worldview through his writing. However, developments in Nazi Germany kept intellectuals in Austria keenly aware of their threatened status. Several of Schütz's closest friends had emigrated beginning in the early 1930s. Schütz was able to make his way out of Vienna to Paris in 1938, where he was soon joined by the rest of his family. From there, it was on to New York, where he continued in the employ of the banking firm Reitler and Associates.
In 1943, Schütz began to teach sociology at the New School for Social Research, while continuing his career in banking. His academic activities increased over the years until, in 1956, he became a full-time professor at the school. He continued to teach and write even when ill health began to curtail his activities in the late 1950s. He died at the age of 60 on May 20, 1959.
A detailed account of Schütz's life, focusing on his work and writings, can be found in Helmut R. Wagner's Alfred Schütz: An Intellectual Biography (Chicago: Univ. of Chicago Press, 1983).
Scope and Contents
The Alfred Schütz Papers consist of manuscripts, course and lecture materials, letters, documentation pertaining to various organizations with which he was affiliated, and personal papers documenting his life and work. The papers span the years 1925-2002, with the bulk concentrated in the two decades before Schütz's death, 1940-59.
The collection is housed in 40 boxes and consists of five series, Manuscripts, Teaching and Research Materials, Subject Files and Correspondence, Personal Papers and Additions Since 2003. Box 35 contains Oversize material. Box 36 contains Restricted Fragile Papers.
Series I, Manuscripts, contains drafts of most of Schütz's essays. Most of the manuscript pages are individually stamped with consecutive numbers. This was apparently done by Lester Embree in 1971 when he prepared his An Outline of the Alfred Schütz Nachlass. His arrangement was based on the order in which he found the manuscripts in Schütz's bookcases. This arrangement has been preserved, as drafts of works were, for the most part, kept together, though the chronological order of the drafts may not be precise. Physical descriptions of the materials have been translated from German into English (e.g. fassung = draft), but titles have not been translated. An additional group of manuscripts donated in 1990 contained drafts of works already accounted for in the Embree listing. These new materials were integrated into the arrangement according to their titles, though they are unnumbered. Therefore, some works may have folders of numbered pages interfiled with folders of unnumbered pages.
Included in this series are drafts of Die Strukturen der Lebenswelt, Phänomenologie und Kulturwissenschaft, On Multiple Realities and Mozart and the Philosophers. Also found here are several essays on other influential writers, such as Edmund Husserl, Max Weber, T. S. Eliot and George Santayana.
In some instances, letters or printed materials were included in, and numbered along with, the drafts of manuscripts. These have been retained in their original places with the manuscripts, but cross-references have been made, where appropriate, from Series II, Subject Files and Correspondence
Series II, Teaching and Research Materials, consists of lecture and course materials prepared for classes which Schütz taught at the New School for Social Research, and reading notes by Schütz on various topics, most of which were realted to the social sciences. As with Series I, this group of materials consists of folders of numbered sheets interfiled with folders of unnumbered sheets.
Series III, Subject Files and Correspondence, contains letters, writings by others, and materials from organizations. These materials made up part of the 1990 donation and were received in an order apparently kept by Alfred Schütz. This group has been kept together in the original received order. Headings for persons and corporate groups are followed by subheadings indicating the type of materials present. (e.g. material relating to Dorion Cairns is divided into Correspondence and a draft of a manuscript).
Among the more complete collections of correspondence are those with H. L. van Breda, Marvin Farber, Eric Voegelin, Fritz Machlup, Maurice Natanson, Kurt Wolff, and with Aron Gurwitsch (this last group having been published as Philosophers in Exile, Richard Grathoff ed., Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 1989). Other correspondents represented in this series include Raymond Aron, Kenneth Burke, Kurt Goldstein, Jean Hyppolite, Karl Löwith, Jacques Maritain, Maurice Merleau-Ponty, Karl Popper, Jacques Rueff, Meyer Schapiro, Leo Strauss, and Jean Wahl. Schütz often kept carbon copies of his letters to his many colleagues, so often, both sides of an epistolary exchange are extant in this archive.
Drafts of manuscripts from fellow social scientists such as Marvin Farber, Aron Gurwitsch, Eric Voegelin and Ludwig von Mises are found in this series. Schütz preserved an amount of correspondence and meeting literature for such events of the Colloque philosophique de Royaumont and the Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion. Included among these are drafts of reports and comments by Schütz. Materials relating to Schütz's tenure at the New School for Social Research include correspondence and graduate faculty memos written by Schütz and others.
Among the Personal Papers in Series IV are résumé fragments and lists of Schütz's publications.
Series V, Additions Since 2003, includes reproductions of annotations Schütz made to books in his library, now held at the Sozialwissenschaftliches Archiv Konstanz. There are 44 reels of microfilm duplicating 162 titles and one CD. The reels include the full text of titles, with Schütz's annotations, and the CD contains JPEG images of pages with annotations in color and Word files documenting color annotations. The reels are arranged in alphabetical order by author and accompanied by a finding aid.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, 1925-1968. II. Teaching and Research Materials, 1940-1959. III. Subject Files and Correspondence, 1927-1979. IV. Personal Papers, 1935-1959. V. April 2013 Acquisition.
Phenomenological sociology -- United States; Phenomenology; Sociology -- History; Sociology -- Germany -- History; Philosophers -- United States; Aron, Raymond, 1905-1983; Goldstein, Kurt, 1878-1965; Gurwitsch, Aron; Löwith, Karl, 1897-1973; Machlup, Fritz, 1902-1983; Maritain, Jacques, 1882-1973; Merleau-Ponty, Maurice, 1908-1961; Natanson, Maurice, 1924-1996; Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund), 1902-1994; Schapiro, Meyer, 1904-1996; Schutz, Alfred, 1899-1959; Strauss, Leo, 1899-1973; Voegelin, Eric, 1901-1985; Wahl, Jean André, 1888-1974; Wolff, Kurt, 1887-1963; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997) -- Faculty
- Writings, 1925-1958; Series I; 5.75; (14 boxes)
  - Vorstudien zu: Der sinnhafte Aufbau der sozialen Welt
    - Notes, lecture notes, contents outline, single manuscript fragment [1-37], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Einige Strukturen der Lebenswelt
    - First version, holograph fragment (German) [38-48], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Second version, holograph (German) [49-79] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - English translation by Aron Gurwitsch, typescript [80-104], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Suggestions for small changes of the translation by Alfred Schütz [105-107], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rationality and the Structure of the Social World
    - Typescript, corrected [119-177], 1940 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Studien zu Talcott Parsons: The Structure of Social Action
    - First version, holograph [178-277], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Earlier version, holograph [178-277], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Extraction from Talcott Parsons' "Toward a General Theory of Action" and "The Social System" [303-429] (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
    - Complete sample copy of Parsons' Theory of Social Action, typescript [430-504], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Correspondence between Schütz and Parsons, particularly about Schütz's manuscript [505-559] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Notes and excerpts from Schütz about Parsons' "The Professions and the Social Structure", "Actor, Situations, and Normative Patterns: An Essay in the Theory of Social Action", and "The Structure of Social Action" [560-584] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence between Schütz and Harold Garfinkel about the differences between Schütz and Parsons [585-594] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Study of Relevance
    - Synoptic table of contents of copied manuscripts and English editions, edited by R. Zaner, dating between Aug. 1947 and Aug. 1951 [595] (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - First part, holograph [596-790], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
    - Second part, holograph [791-815] (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Philosophie der Leerstelle, holograph [816-829], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - The Biographical Situation, holograph [830-854], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Notes and background materials, holograph [855-884] (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Zu Wilhelm Meisters Wanderjahren
    - Draft, holograph [885-1039], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - Don Quixote
    - Studies on Cervantes' Don Quixote, holograph [1040-1093], 1953 Jul (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Don Quixote and the Problem of Reality, first version, holograph (unedited and unabridged) [1094-1165], 1953 Jul-Aug (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Fourth version, holograph [1166-1206], 1953 Dec (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Don Quixote and the Problem of Reality, draft typescript [1207-1251], 1953 Dec (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Don Quixote and the Problem of Reality, draft typescript, corrected, 1953 Dec 1 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Albert Salomon: Don Quixote's Social Mission, typescript [1252-1284], 1953 Nov (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - On Max Scheler's Epistemology and Ethics
    - Notes and first formulation, holograph [1285-1381] (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    - Draft with appendix by Ilse Schütz, typescript [1382-1414] (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Scheler's Theory of Intersubjectivity
    - Comments and notes, holograph [1415-1426] (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Early draft, holograph [1427-1511], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 41-42)
    - Last draft (?), holograph [1512-1573], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Scheler's Theory of Intersubjectivity and the General Thesis of the Alter Ego, drafts, typescript carbon, corrected [1574-1614] (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Max Scheler
    - First formulation, holograph [1615-1620], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Draft, holograph [1621-1668], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Scheler essay, third draft, typescript [1669-1687], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Bibliography of Secondary Literature, holograph [1688-1690] (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Translation of Concepts, holograph [1691-1693], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Excerpts, holograph [1694-1734], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - First drafts, holograph [1735-1801], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 52-53)
    - On Max Scheler's Epistemology and Ethics, holograph [1802-1806] (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - On Max Scheler's Epistemology and Ethics, draft, typescript, corrected [1807-1842] (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - On Multiple Realities
    - First draft, holograph, [1843-1875], 1940 Jul (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Second draft, holograph, [1876-1923], 1943 Jul (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Notes, holograph [1924-1937], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Draft (after "First draft"): The Worlds of Work, Imagination, Dream and Social Science. Life World and Social Sciences. From Working to Theorizing. (On Finite Provinces of Meaning), typescript, corrected, photocopy (includes carbon of letter from Ilse Schütz to Lester Embree, 1973 Dec 29 [1938-1969], 1940-43 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1944 Sep 30 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Draft, holograph, [1970-2075], 1944 Sep (Box 4, Folder 61-62)
    - Comments, holograph [2076-2082], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Draft, typescript carbon, [2083-2155], 1944 Sep (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - William James' Concept of the Stream of Thought, Phenomenologically Interpreted
    - Draft and loose pages, holograph [2156-2216] (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Draft, typescript [2217-2233], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Das Problem der transzendentalen Intersubjectivität bei Hüsserl
    - Last draft, holograph, [2234-2308], 1957 Mar 16 (Box 4, Folder 67-68)
    - Second draft, holograph (incomplete) [2309-2324] (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - First draft, holograph (incomplete) [2325-2348], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Notes, holograph [2349-2352], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Excerpts and others from "Fink, Kantstudienaufsatz", holograph [2353-2358] (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Draft, typescript, [2359-2402], 1957 Apr (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Discussion notes [2403-2414], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Edmund Husserl
    - Draft, holograph [2415-2458], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Troisième colloque philosophique de Royaumont
    Scope and Contents
    Held 1957 Apr. 23-30
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Series II, Colloque Philosophique de Royaumont, Box 20, folders 451-456
    - Letter from Dorian Cairns to Schütz [2459], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Colloquium program [2460-2463], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Contributions by:
      - K. Kuypers [2464-2471], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Philip Merlan [2472-2498], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Alphonse de Waelhens [2499-2509], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Stephan[?] Strasser [2510-2521], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - Cornelis Anthonie von Peursen [2522-2531], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Eugen Fink [2532-2543], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Roman Ingarden [2544-2564], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - Antonio Banfi [2565-2574], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Contribution by Schütz (French) typescript [2575-2617], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Discussion notes [2618-2631], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Discussion speech by Alfred Schütz, holograph [108-118], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Comments on Schütz's paper by Eugen Fink, typescript [5904-5926], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Equality and the Meaning Structure of the Social World
    - Draft, holograph [2632-2735], 1955 Jul (Box 5, Folder 90-91)
    - Later(?) version, holograph [2736-2757], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Notes and earlier formulations, holograph [2758-2807] (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Excerpts from William Graham Sumner's Folkways, holograph [2808-2827], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Draft, typescript [2828-2897], 1955 Jul (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Mozart and the Philosophers
    - Background materials, holograph [2898-3011], 1955 Fall (Box 5, Folder 96-97)
    - Draft, typescript [3110-3136], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Discussion notes, holograph [3137-3138], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Draft, holograph and typescript [3139-3182] (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Draft, typescript [3183-3211], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected (with clipping announcing Schütz's lecture), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Making Music Together
    - Draft, holograph [3012-3055], 1950 Aug (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 Aug 1 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Earlier version, holograph [3056-3078], 1947 Aug (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Background materials, holograph [3079-3109] (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Choosing among Projects of Action
    - On Choice and Decision, holograph [3213-3266], 1945 Sep 8 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Materials from "On Choice and Decision" [3267-3338], 1945 Aug (Box 6, Folder 108-109)
    - Paralipomena to the paper "Choosing among Projects of Action", typescript [3339-3362], 1945 Sep 8 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Choosing between Projects of Action, holograph [3363-3417], 1950 Aug 14 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Background materials, loose pages, holograph [3418-3428] (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Common Sense and Science
    - First manuscript version, possible formulation variants, holograph [3429-3638], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 113-116)
    - Common Sense and Scientific Model Constructs of Human Action and the Concept of Rationality, holograph [3639-3765], 1952 (Box 6, Folder 117-118)
    - The Problem of Rationality in the Social World, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - The Problem of Rationality in the Social World, draft, typescript [3766-3805], 1940 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Sartre's Theory of the Alter Ego
    - Early version, holograph [3806-3861], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Draft, holograph [3862-3932], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 122-123)
    - Materials, holograph [3933-3987], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Draft, typescript [3988-4019], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - The Homecomer
    - Abstracts [1944 Jul 13], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - First notes [4020-4024], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Draft, holograph [4025-4062], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Drafts, typescript carbons, corrected [4063-4080 and unnumbered] (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Review of Husserl's Ideas
    - Draft, holograph, [4081-4139], 1952 Aug 5 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Manuscript parts and materials, holograph [4140-4190] (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Husserl: "Ideen II und III"
    - Abbreviated rough translation by Schütz, typescript, corrected [4191-4466], 1952 Apr-Oct (Box 7, Folder 132-136)
    - Abbreviated rough translation by Schütz, typescript carbon, corrected, 1952 Apr-Oct (Box 7, Folder 137-139)
    - Prefatory notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Freely translated (abridged) version for private purposes by Schütz and Maurice Natanson, typescript [5222-5498] (Box 8, Folder 141-145)
  - Concept and Theory Formation in the Social Sciences
    - Last draft, typescript [4467-4493], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Earlier version, typescript with holograph corrections [4494-4540], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Manuscript drafts
      - Introduction, holograph [4541-4543], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 148)
      - Draft No. 3, holograph [4544-4561], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 149)
      - Draft No. 4 and 5, holograph [4562-4569] (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - Draft No. 5, holograph [4570-4592], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 151)
      - Draft No. 4, holograph [4593-4611], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 152)
      - Fragments, holograph [4612-4623], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 153)
      - Draft with setting typescript and notes (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Symbol, Reality, and Society
    - Notes and abstract, holograph and typescript carbon (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Early draft, holograph, [4624-4661], 1954 May 29 (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Draft, holograph, [4662-4746], 1954 Jun 12 (Box 8, Folder 157-158)
    - Last draft, holograph and typescript [4747-4863], 1954 Jul 11 (Box 8, Folder 159-160)
    - Draft, typescript [4864-4955], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 161-162)
  - Teiresias
    - Second draft, holograph [4956-5006], 1944 Aug 5 (Box 9, Folder 163)
    - First draft, holograph [5007-5059], 1944 Jul 31 (Box 9, Folder 164)
    - Version prepared for lecture at the Philosophic Club of Columbia University, draft, holograph [5060-5108], 1958 Mar 13 (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Version prepared for lecture at the Philosophic Club of Columbia University, drafts, typescript carbon [5109-5131], 1958 Mar 13 (Box 9, Folder 166)
  - Santayana on Society and Government
    - Draft, holograph [5132-5187], 1951 Jul 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Draft, typescript, corrected [5188-5221], 1951 Jul 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected [5188-5221], 1951 Jul 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - Die Strukturen der Lebenswelt
    - Notes on contents of notebooks, holograph [5499-5506], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Notebook I, holograph [5507-5579], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Notebook II, holograph [5580-5653], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Notebook III, holograph [5754-5853], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Notebook IV, holograph [5654-5753], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Notebook V, holograph [5854-5903], 1958 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Notecards outlining book [5779-5828 and unnumbered], 1958 (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - The Stranger: An Essay in Social Psychology
    - Introduction draft, holograph, corrected, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Draft, holograph, [5977-6049], 1942 Aug (Box 10, Folder 178-179)
    - Second draft, holograph, [6050-6102], 1942 Aug-Sep (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Second draft, typescript, [6103-6132], 1942 Aug-Sep (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - New draft, holograph [6133-6155], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - New draft, typescript [6156-6176], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Discussion notes, holograph [6177-6180], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - The Well Informed Citizen
    - First draft, [6181-6223], 1945 Aug (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Draft, holograph, [6224-6264], 1946 Sep (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Draft, typescript [6265-6285], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 187)
  - Language, Language Disturbances, and the Texture of Mind
    - Draft, holograph, [6286-6340], 1949 Dec 25 (Box 11, Folder 188)